Ana Carolina Lemos

Software developer

L +55 (19) 98205-5713 **Carol1692@hotmail.com**

Piracicaba, São Paulo, Brasil

I'm an I.T professional with about 8 years of experience, transiting between I.T areas as web development, monitoring execution tests, support to cloud servers solving security vulnerabilities and support to middlewares. During all my work journey have the presence and contact with international and Brazilians clients

Skills:

- Python
- Javascript
- Flask
- Django
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Selenium
- Pytest
- SOAP UI

- SQL
- SQL Alchemy
- PostgreSQL
- DB2 IBM
- Linux
- IBM Tivoli Workload Scheduler (TWS)
- Git
- GitHub

Work Experience:

Web Developer - Back-End

Company: EY - Ernst & Young

Dates: 02/2023 - 02/2024

As consultant work developing application for a great brazilian stateowned company. At first helping team adapt the old features and after the maintenance part being responsible to develop new features. From this moment I started to work as well as front-end developer. On this project i was able to use Python and Javascript as main languages, framework Flask using Agile to manage our backlog

QA tester

Company: IBM

Dates: 10/2022 - 01/2023

Worked as API tester, using SoapUI. Was responsible to send payloads tests and document the results aiming for the tests quality.

Application Developer - Monitoring and Python Automation

Company: IBM

Dates: 03/2021 - 10/2022

As a consultant for the AT&T project within IBM, I was responsible for monitoring the management team, serving global customers, investigating problems, and directing them to the necessary team in case of errors in the execution tests. Along with monitoring, we also took the initiative to automate manually performed processes and display them on a web dashboard, allowing the customer to have more autonomy regarding the status of the tests. In the web project, I was responsible for working with Python, creating messaging with SMTP, and creating routes for sending data to the front-end.



I was recognized as a standout on the team for my quick adaptation and skills demonstrated on a daily basis.

Infrastructure Specialist - Security Support

Company: IBM

Dates: 03/2018 - 02/2021

During my 4 years in the DevSecOps project, I started as a queue manager, where I was responsible for analyzing support requests and distributing them among teammates, seeking to balance the workload between them. After this first experience, I started supporting the Rational solution for Collaborative Lifecycle Management (CLM) and UrbanCode Deploy applications. As my last role within the team, I worked with security demands, helping to resolve vulnerabilities in operating systems and some server-level applications.

Education:

 Graduated, Analysis and Development of Systems, Universidade Estadual de Campinas (Unicamp), BR

Courses/certificates:

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals.
- Python for begginers
- <u>Bootcamp Backend Developer</u>

In progress:

- Python Django The Practical Guide
- Bootcamp Frontend Developer

Languages:

- Portuguese Fluent
- English B1/B2

 At moment studying Spanish and French